Subindex build by Thomson
NETFLIX 呈献
您身为军人
How could a soldier steal royal treasures
怎么能因为国家灭亡
就要偷窃王室的财宝呢？
just because the country is ruined?
高丽不会阵亡
Goryeo will not fall.
如果你是真正的忠臣
If you are truly a loyal man,
就不要阻拦我
do not stand in my way.
将军
General.
（1388年李成桂从威华岛回军
IN 1388, YI SEONG-GYE TURNED HIS ARMY AROUND IN WIHWADO
随后崔莹将军出兵 但败给李成桂后被抓
GENERAL CHOE YEONG SENT HIS MEN BUT WERE DEFEATED
高丽的最后一根支柱倒塌了）
THUS THE LAST PILLAR OF GORYEO FELL
（觉察到危机的一些高丽将军 掠夺了王室的财物
GORYEO GENERALS WHO FELT THE THREAT STOLE THE KINGDOM TREASURES
并逃到了远海）
AND FLED FAR OUT TO SEA
（朝鲜太祖4年）
I mean,
话说
我知道我们是盗贼
I know that we're thieves鈥?
但为什么被当作逆贼被追呢？
鈥ut why are we being pursued as traitors?
因为做了谋反行为
Well鈥?
鈥e did commit treason.
头目 这是什么意思？
What are you talking about?
快要死到临头了 我告诉你真相吧
We'll be in the afterlife soon, so I'll be truthful.
你记得吗？
Do you remember
三陟树
the Samcheok tree?
记得 用它制作了这个勺子啊
Of course. I made this spoon out of it.
我可是第一次见那种树
- This one? - I've never seen a tree like that.
那是新宫殿的栋梁
That was for the pillars of the new palace.
栋梁？
The pillars?
新宫殿的话
The new palace in Gyeongbokgung.
是指李成桂为了搬迁到汉阳
The one Yi Seong-gye's building in Hanyang to make it to the capital?
而建造的景福宫吗？
为了寻找支撑景福宫的栋梁
Yi Seong-gye searched all over the country
李成桂搜索了全国各地
to find wood for the pillars to support Gyeongbokgung
然后在太白山顶找到了那棵树
and found that tree at the top of Taebaeksan.
我们在广渡口偷的是那个东西吗？
The one we stole in Gwangnaru?
味道怎么样？
How'd it taste?
用景福宫栋梁盛着吃的饭
Eating with the pillars of Gyeongbokgung?
是不是很香？
- Good?
景福宫没有建完是因为…
The reason they stopped building Gyeongbokgung鈥?
都是因为
It's all鈥?
这个勺子
because of this spoon.
为什么？
Why?
为什么那么做？
Why did you do it?
为了吃饭麻麻香吗？
Probably not just to eat with it?
千年王国的栋梁是三陟树还是百姓？
Are the pillars of a thousand-year dynasty supposed to be a tree or the people?
因为他们看不到眼前的 只从远处找
His vision never included what was right in front of his eyes.
所以我心气不顺
Really got on my nerves.
就因为你心气不顺
So because it got on your nerves--
让成百上千的官军追赶我们？
You made thousands of soldiers chase after us.
可能现在还在追赶我们
They're probably still after us.
你还笑？
- You're laughing?
笑？他妈的
- Dammit! Let me go!
人死后就不会口渴了吧
If I die, will my thirst die as well?
我先走一天 安顿好了等你们
I'll go a day early to save you all seats when I get there.
我要砍了你的头！
- I'll cut off your head!
放开我！
- Oh get off! - Let me go.
放手 你这个混蛋！
Let me go!
放开我！
来了
So they've come, at last.
来接我了
They've come to take me.
是阴间使者还是仙女？
Are you a woman who lives in the land of the gods?
怎么可以如此漂亮？
How can someone be so beautiful?
竟然死后才遇见命中之人
That I should have to die to meet my destiny.
来
Here.
带我走吧
Take me with you.
起来
Get up.
真是的
别叫我
Leave me alone.
我叫你起来
- You're not getting up?
（获救三个月后）
THREE MONTHS AFTER THE RESCUE
一
One.
二
- Two.
我先穿衣服
Let me put on some clothes first.
团长
Captain, how long are we keeping these bandits on our ship?
你打算让这些盗贼留在船上多久？
他们太懒了 随处拉屎 这帮家伙们太脏了
They're extremely lazy.
They poop anywhere they
like, the disgusting, dirty bastards.
我一直搞不明白这条船
I have no idea what kind of ship this is.
这是海盗船吗？
Is it a pirate ship?
这是海盗船还是渔船？
Are you pirates or fishermen?
而且只劫倭寇船
And if they're pirates, why only attack Japanese pirates?
就是啊 打劫商船才有钱买肉吃啊
You must attack merchant ships for the money to feast on meat.
我们是朝鲜海军吗？ 为什么只劫持倭寇？
We're like the Joseon navy, only attacking the Japanese.
就是说啊
- Exactly! - Ugh.
一股鱼腥味 光是看着就厌倦了
Getting sick just from looking at seafood.
- Ugh. Filthy.
-是谁？ -脏死了
Who did that?
谁把珍贵的粮食扔了？
Who threw precious food on the deck?
是谁把珍贵的粮食扔了？
She asked who threw food on the deck.
是你啊
Who? It was you.
一帮忘恩负义的家伙们！
I've had it with these ungrateful bastards!
-走吧 -盗贼们集合
- Get over here, you thieving scums! - Go on!
-盗贼 -是你扔的嘛 快过去
- Thieving scum. - You did it. It was you.
不是你扔的嘛
Go on. Hurry up.
都给我过来！
Come here. Now!
我是海盗
Uh, I'm a pirate.
-没见过你啊 -刚来第五天
- Never see you before. - This is my fifth day.
-滚 -是
- Dismissed! - Yes, sir.
你又是谁？
Something funny?
义贼们 过来吧
Bandits, come here.
过来
Come here!
- Come here! - Yeah. I didn't think so.
过来！
Come here!
-过来！ -过来！
- Come here! - Come here!
那边有倭寇！
Japanese pirates! Japanese pirates on the horizon!
Japanese pirates on the horizon!
- Japanese pirate ship?
Woohoo! Yeah!
看他们倭寇船还挺有钱的样子！
Hey! They look pretty rich for a Japanese pirate ship!
看来可以吃肉了！
Huh? We'll be eating meat soon enough.
团长 我会烤出世界上最好吃的味道
Captain, I'll cook you the world's most delicious steak.
牛肉用炭火烤
Let's slowly grill the beef over the fire.
猪肉就煮熟了吃！
And we'll feast on boiled pork!
宝物！
Black clouds. Strong winds.
乌云巨浪！
真是一个舞剑的好天气！
It's perfect weather for sword-fighting.
乌云巨浪？
Black clouds and strong winds?
喂 你会用剑吗？
Hey. Do you even know how to use a sword? Huh?
你可能不知道
Ah, you've heard of me.
虽然我在这里是负责晒鱿鱼的
Up until now, I've only dried squid, but trust me,
但在那片陆地上
on the mainland, they call me Goryeo's Greatest Swordsman!
我被称为高丽第一剑客！
展示一下你的实力如何？
I guess we'll see about that.
高丽第一剑客？
Goryeo's Greatest Swordsman?
-真好笑 -都让开！
Out of my way!
是时候展现真正的实力了！
All right! The time has finally come!
今天由我们义贼团率领！
Today, we bandits will stand on the frontline!
你们海盗
You pirates stay here and prepare to feast on the meat!
就留下来准备肉宴吧！
禹武治
Mu-chi!
别得瑟了 快下来
Stop all your bragging and come down!
别担心我 开火等着吧 娘子
Don't worry about me.
And build the fire, my lady.
不是 团长
I mean, Captain.
来 我们走！
Come on!
Let's go!
火力全开！
Full speed ahead!
Come on! Come on!
不是渔船吗？
Perhaps it isn't a fishing boat?
是渔船
I'm sure it is a fishing boat.
高丽第一剑客出马！
The best swordsman in Goryeo is coming!
是海盗！
Hey, you bastards!
那是鱼线吗？
And I suppose these are fishing rods?
拉过来！
Pull!
再使劲儿！
More! A bit more!
大家随我来！
Yes! Follow my lead!
Go!
傻子
- Idiot.
-我们上 -停下！
- Let's go! - Hold on!
我不需要海盗的帮助！
We don't need help from pirates!
团长 我需要帮助！
We do need help, Captain!
帮帮我们吧 团长！
Please, help us!
把剑给我
- Lend me your sword. - Damn it.
该死
- Help!
救命！
没有碍手碍脚的家伙 打起来会更轻松
Whoo.
I'll have an easier time fighting
without those guys getting in the way.
杀了他！
Kill him!
厉害
Amazing.
禹武治！
- Mu-chi!
我倒要瞧瞧你的实力
Let's see what you can do, Mu-chi.
还笑？
You're laughing?
我手里可是拿着刀呢
I'm holding a sword.
咦？
Oh.
高丽第一剑客
Goryeo's Greatest Swordman.
厉害！
- Amazing!
Amazing! Truly amazing!
真的好厉害！
Shut up!
这是朝鲜的海
These waters belong to Joseon.
你们掠夺了我们的海洋
Because you have plundered in our waters,
所以我都要讨回来
I will be taking that plunder back.
这里是我们的
This is ours鈥?
你们的… 我们的…
Yours鈥?Ours鈥?
我们是沿着海流流动的人
We are sea-faring folk who follow the current.
对于大海 没有你我之分
We make no distinction between our waters and your waters.
说完了吗？
Done?
他说这里也是他们的海
They say these are their waters too.
太短了吧？
What?
That's all, Captain.
团长 我十岁之前一直住在倭寇船上
That's a bit short.
I lived on a Japanese
pirate ship until I was ten.
全部
These
都是你们的海吗？
are all your waters?
全都是你们的吗？
All yours?
白痴 我不是这个意思…
You idiot. That's not what I said--
混蛋！
Shut up!
他说大海都是他们的
He's saying the entire sea is theirs!
团长
Captain.
我搜遍了也没有找到肉
I looked everywhere, but there isn't any meat.
连鸡肉都没有吗？
- There isn't even anything like chicken?
不知道 这帮家伙们
Hey. I have no idea.
好像只吃腌鱼
All this crew eats is pickled fish.
我去找找
让开 我去找找
Please spare us!
放过我们吧！
我们只是…
We're just鈥?
闭嘴！
Shut up!
我们只是来寻找宝物的
We just came here in search of treasure.
巨大的宝物…
A huge stash of gold and silver鈥?
去死吧！
I'll kill you!
他说什么？
What did he say?
Oh.
他说
He鈥?he says they're on a search for
来寻找巨大的宝物
an enormous stash of treasure.
Treasure?
宝物在哪里？
Boy, tell me. Where's this treasure?
宝物 哪里？
Where's the treasure?
我？
Me?
这好像是高丽军营使用的地图
This looks like the maps they use in Goryeo military camps.
没错
Yeah. It is.
我也用过
I used ones just like this.
朱芳
"Joo Bang."
将帅朱芳
General Joo Bang,
带领高丽王室禁卫军的那个朱芳吗？
who led the Goryeo Imperial Guard?
据说席卷了高丽王室的宝物 消失在海里
That Joo Bang?
The one who swept up the
treasure of the imperial family and disappeared?
这是大将军朱芳的藏宝图吗？
You mean this is General Joo Bang's treasure map?
是朱芳的宝物
They said it's Joo Bang's treasure.
有肉吃了！
We could eat meat!
安静！
Quiet! Quiet.
臭小子 你个老幺喊什么！
Why you little鈥?How dare you tell us to be quiet!
团长 我们出发吧
Captain, let's do it.
只要得到这个宝物
If we get this treasure, we'll never have to look at another damn squid ever again.
这该死的鱿鱼也不用晒了
不用晒鱿鱼了
拜托
Oh, please, please.
怎么样？
- Huh?
这可是宝物啊
It's treasure. Treasure!
走吧
- Please? - Huh?
好！
Okay!
扬帆起航
Let's raise our sails.
出发吧！
我们去寻宝吧！
-拉起来！ -拉起来！
Let's go!
龙女上岸之后无法施力了啊
So I see the dragon's daughter is at a loss
when it comes to being on land.
这不就在这儿嘛
Oh, here. Look, it's right here.
真是的 竟然看不出这个
Don't tell me you can't see it.
- Seriously鈥?
给我吧
Come on!
海里靠龙 陆上还得靠虎吧？
The dragon is master of the sea, but the tiger wins on land.
Uh鈥?
听好了！从现在开始听我指挥！
Right!
You'll follow me from now on!
我们走！
Let's go!
放马过来吧！
Greet your guests!
高丽第一剑客禹武治 和他的手下们来了！
Goryeo's Greatest Swordsman, Wu Mu-chi, and his men have arrived!
什么声音？
What was that?
What?
什么声音？
他召唤出了什么东西？
What the hell did he yell at?
-那是什么？ -那边
Over there! Over there!
You saw it!
看到了吗？
- A cow!
是牛！
Do you see it?
A cow!
牛肉先送上门了！
Looks like the meat is coming to greet us first!
寻宝之前先填饱肚子吧！
Before finding the treasure, let's fill our bellies!
住手 别胡来！
- Stop! Do not act out of line.
都跟着我！
Head to the tunnel!
Come on!
牛
Cows! Cows! Cows!
回来！
- No! Come back! - Turn around!
快回来！
No! Come back!
怎么了？
Why?
快躲好！
Get out of the way!
回去！
Turn around!
What's happening?
头目！
Boss!
Why?
他生前那么嚣张
He was too full of himself鈥?
这一生真虚无缥缈
He died such a sudden death after living such a lowly life.
只留下了一个勺子
Leaving behind only his spoon.
团长
Captain.
我们出发吧
We should go.
团长 看那边
Captain, look! Look! Look over there!
怎么活下来的？
How did he survive?
我回来了！
Look who's back, huh?
那是什么？
海浪
- Here. Your hand.
姜燮
Kang-seop.
终于明白地图上为什么有象牙了
Now I understand why there's a tusk drawn on the map.
这才是真正的藏宝图
This is the real treasure map.
-我们回船上开庆宴吧 -好的 团长
Let us return to the ship and feast.
- Yes, Captain.
藏宝图
A treasure map. A treasure map.
牛群蜂拥而至 为什么还进山洞里？
Why would you enter the cave when there's a herd of cows coming?
我也受伤了
I'm injured too.
真是的
Honestly, unbelievable.
我早就觉得那个洞有问题
I had a bad feeling about that cave.
谁在那哭唧唧啊？
Who's making that damn whiny noise?
盗贼们听好了！
You thieves, listen here!
是义贼
I said we're honest bandits.
我看你们被当成高丽逆贼
I took you in because I pitied how you all fled to sea
逃到海里很可怜 所以收留了你们
after being branded as traitors to Goryeo.
但没想到你们会一直赖着不走
But I didn't think you'd stick around with us.
这段时间你们也养肥了
Seeing how fat you've grown since then,
现在是时候跟你们说了
I think the time has come to tell you.
想让我们离开吗？
Are you telling us to leave?
不
Listen!
自此海盗船
From this moment on, on my ship,
只许海盗上船
only pirates can sail with us.
海盗
- Pirate!
如果义贼变成海盗呢？
And if a bandit becomes a pirate?
接受
Then I'll accept him.
姜燮 你是副头目 所以任命你为跟阿贵一样的小团长
Kang-seop, as you're second-in-command, I'll name you as first mate with A-gwi.
团长
Captain!
我们变成海盗了吗？
Are we pirates now too?
合作愉快
This will be good.
Hey!
喂 你凭什么任命副头目为小团长！
Hey. Who said you could name him as your first mate, huh?
禹武治
Wu Mu-chi, I will鈥?
任命你为副团长
make you my quartermaster.
让我当你的属下？
You'll make me your underling?
我可是高丽第一剑客禹武治
Wu Mu-chi, Goryeo's Greatest Swordsman?
就像海里容不下两个龙王
Just as the sea has only one Dragon King,
海盗团也只能有一个团长
a pirate crew can have only one captain.
难道不是你想成为蜂王吗？
You're not just trying to play queen bee?
说话注意点
Watch what you say, Quartermaster.
副团长
Be careful.
谁是副团长！
Don't call me quartermaster!
看看那些跟着你的盗贼们！
Take a second to look at your bandits, Mu-chi!
我们的生活每天都是生死攸关的战场
Every day is like a war, balanced on the line between life and death.
如果两个人下令就率领不了团队
You cannot lead a group if you confuse them with two different orders.
你是在叫我离开吗？
You telling me to go?
看来你想离开了
If that's what you want.
大家听好了！
Listen to me!
我要离开船并留在这里
I'm abandoning the ship and staying here.
看看那边
Look there!
那片海里没有什么路
The path by sea is unclear.
谁要和我一起走正义之路？
Who will walk the righteous path with me?
没关系 坐着吧 反正你们会留下来
It's fine. Stay seated. You're staying here with me anyway.
保重
Don't get sick.
一起走
- I'm coming too. - Beats being a bandit.
走吧！
Let's go!
从现在开始跟随我的人
Those who follow me are known as pirates from here on out.
都是海盗
-海盗 -保重
Take care.
真的没有人跟随我吗？
Is there really no one who will follow me?
-一 二 -快来吧 大哥
One, two. One, two.
瞧
Those鈥?
不讲义气的家伙们
Look at those disloyal morons, huh?
姜燮 你才是真正的义贼
Kang-seop, you stand for what a bandit should stand for.
-所谓义贼… -多谢了 头目
- For what is a bandit? Those united by-- - Thank you for everything, boss.
义无反顾… 什么？
保重身体 小心官军
Take care of yourself and watch out for soldiers.
姜燮 你…
You'd鈥?Hang on, Kang-seop!
等一下 姜燮
姜燮
- Come on, man. - Hurry up!
-推 -快推
- Wait for me! - Come on. It's you and me!
-等等我！ -姜燮 你和我 禹武治
Now, Wu Mu-chi--
-你们等等我啊！ -姜燮
I said wait for me!
Kang-seop.
过来
Stay here!
Come back here!
-过来！ -等一下
- Come back here! - Wait!
一 二！
One, two!
好 走吧！
Go on, then! Go!
太棒了！
Good riddance!
真棒！
听说你在龟州斩了女真族首领的头…
I'd heard that you killed the leader of Jurchen in Kuju.
（李芳远）
YI BANG-WON
…看来并不是虚张声势
- It appears that was true.
王位？
The throne, you say?
你觉得我率领几百名士兵 是想占据王位吗？
So you think I took command of a few hundred soldiers just to take the throne?
但士兵人数很少
You don't have enough men for that
我觉得不够严谨
and, also, they seem unprepared.
你是个真正的逆贼
You are the real traitor.
多谢您的认可
I appreciate it, you remembering that.
你想说什么？
Just come out with it.
财物
Prosperity.
王位要靠权力夺取 而不是靠阶级
One does not claim the throne through rank but rather with power.
权力来自兵力 其基础唯有财物
You can have an army with wealth, and with an army comes power.
我没有那种财物
I don't have wealth, I must admit.
如果某处藏有宝物
If I told you there was a hidden treasure,
您是否想得到？
will you take it?
没错 这才是海盗喝的酒！
Now this is a pirate ale!
喂 给我
Hey. Give it here.
现在宝物在我们手中了 别担心 尽情吃吧！
The treasure is now within our hands!
他有没有吃饭呢？
Well, I wonder if he ate anything.
要不要我去悄悄带他来？
Shall I go and quietly bring him back here?
如果他想来 他早就游到这里了
If he wanted to come, he would have swum here already.
好饱啊
I'm so full.
Captain!
团长
Man鈥?
象牙不见了！
The elephant tusk is gone!
什么不见了？
What? What is gone?
-象牙不见了 -谁干的？
- The elephant tusk is gone! - Who did this?
还能是谁？
Who do you think did it?
这肮脏的小偷
Ugh. That dirty, thieving bastard!
亏我还认他为头目
I can't believe I ever called him boss.
（取回遗失物 高丽第一剑客）
Dammit!
禹武治！
- Wu Mu-chi!
禹武治 被我抓到你就死定了
Wu Mu-chi, I'm going to kill you if I ever catch you!
但他为什么留下标记了呢？
Why do you think he left us his location?
真蠢
That idiot.
说不定这个混蛋设下了陷阱
Hold on. Is this a trap?
陷阱？
A trap?
我认识他很久了
I've known him a long time.
他没这么狡猾
He's not that cunning. Trust me.
是什么东西在吼？
What is this growling?
声势浩大
What else will growl like that?
除了老虎还有什么？
It has to be a tiger.
老虎？
A tiger?
快跑！
- Run away!
浪儿？
Rang?
-这是梦还是现实啊？ -我要杀了你这个小偷
- Is this real, or a dream? - I'm going to kill you, you damn thief!
-希望这不是梦 -我要杀了你
- It would be nice if it weren't a dream. - I'm going to kill you!
你这个混蛋小偷
好痛
That hurt!
- Ow!
-等等 -去死吧
- Get up! - Wait! Wait a moment!
为什么来找我？
Why did you return?
这么快就想我了吗？
Did you miss me already?
因为你是盗贼 所以偷东西也这么理直气壮吗？
Are you proud of your thievery because you're originally a thief?
海浪 我说过我是义贼
Hey, Hae-rang. I told you I'm honest.
等一下
All right, wait. Just wait.
听我说
Listen to me.
象牙是谁找到的？
Who discovered the tusk?
是我找到的 但你总说我偷…
I discovered it, but you--
总说我偷窃
You call it thievery.
我就说两件事
Yeah. I only have a couple things to say to you.
一 偷窃兄弟的财物必须死
Hmm.
One, you should die for the
crime of stealing from your brothers.
都说了是我找到的
I'm the one that found it.
二 把象牙还回来 我就不杀你
Two, simply return the tusk to me and I won't kill you.
这个威胁真有意思
What an impressive threat.
你忘了我的身份吗？高丽第一剑客
Did you forget? Greatest swordsman.
-连咆哮的老虎都可以… -住嘴
- Even a crying tiger-- - Please stop!
再也不要在我面前提“虎”这个字
Never say the "ger" in tiger in front of me again.
虎
等一下
Hey! Hey! Wait!
Stop!
你真的想杀我啊
You're really trying to kill me! Dammit!
给我象牙
Give me the tusk.
-没有 -是吗？
- I don't have it. - Really?
你说实话 我就告诉你
Answer honestly and I'll tell you.
你来找我 真的是因为象牙吗？
Did you find me because of the tusk,
不是因为想我吗？
or because you missed me?
小幕拿走了
- Mak-yi took it.
头目
- Boss.
象牙？
The tusk?
有小偷！
Thief!
你想自己去寻宝私吞吗？
What, were you planning to find the treasure and keep it all to yourself?
-我看起来那么卑鄙吗？ -不然呢？
- Do I look that dishonorable? - Then what?
很快就会来找我下跪的
Soon she'll come to find me and beg me on her knees.
谁？海浪团长吗？
Who? Captain Hae-rang?
所以你打算以象牙为条件 重新回来当头目？
So your plan is to use the tusk as leverage
to get your position back as boss?
我说
Tell me,
反正都要回去 怎么还带上了被子？
why bring a blanket if you're planning on going back anyway?
是我考虑不周
I wasn't thinking straight.
反正已经上了同一条船
Now that we've sailed here together,
听好了 头目
our fates are linked, huh?
-这里四面八方都是官军 -官军？
There are soldiers in every direction here.
所以熟悉山势的头目先上山顶
- Soldiers? - Yeah.
Since you know the mountains now,
you climb to the peak first.
山顶？
To the peak?
如果觉得安全 就把火石
And if the coast is clear, strike your flint.
啪啪打两次
Clack, clack twice.
-两次 -然后我带着行李上去
- Twice. - And I'll follow with the baggage.
- Mm-hmm.
对
Right.
-对 -对
- Right. - Right.
-对 -好
- You're right. - Okay.
Uh-uh.
行李由手下拎着
Leave this to your subordinate.
头目应该想大事 而不是干杂活
Boss, you need to focus on the bigger stuff, not chores.
你
You鈥?
小幕 你…
Mak-yi, a subordinate?
等我回归了 就命你为副团长
Upon my return,
you're my quartermaster.
-头目 -嗯
- Yes, boss. - Yeah.
打几次火石？
How many strikes?
-两次 -两次
- Twice. - Twice.
好 快去吧
Right. Go on, quickly.
-好 去吧 -小幕
- You got this.
快去吧
Go on, quickly!
-好 -去啊
- Go. Go on. - Right.
往左边走
To the left.
真的
Chump.
太单纯了
So na茂ve.
那晚
That night,
我一遍一遍地点燃了火石
I kept striking the flint all night long.
傻子
Idiot.
海盗都是这种人
Starting to feel like all you pirates are like that.
别说笑了
No more self-pity.
一个叫禹武治的家伙在卖象牙的传闻
The rumor is spreading that Wu Mu-chi is selling the tusk.
已经传遍了大海
It has already spread even across the sea.
小幕 这个狗崽子
Mak-yi, son of a--
（碧澜渡）
BYEOKRANDO
-你不能进去 -让开
- You can't go in there! - Out of my way!
对不起 这个人蛮不讲理
I'm so sorry, sir. He just burst his way in.
我这里有件珍宝
I've come because I have a rare item.
我是高丽第一剑客禹武治
I am Wu Mu-chi, Goryeo's Greatest Swordsman.
禹武治 就是和海浪在一起的人？
The one with Hae-rang? That Wu Mu-chi?
您知道我卑微的履历 真是惭愧
I'm embarrassed that you know my humble history.
在我平定广阔的大海之后
After conquering the vast ocean,
把团长海浪当成妹妹一样疼爱
I cared for Hae-rang just like a sworn sister.
快打招呼吧
Let me introduce.
您贵姓？
Who?
海浪
Hae-rang.
谁？
Who is?
我
I am?
节俭点 一万两
Only 10,000 nyang.
大象牙齿一万两是节俭吗？
Only 10,000 nyang for an elephant tooth?
看来您不知道传说
It's what that legend is about.
什么传说？
What legend?
高丽王国被闪电击中的那一天
It was a day when lightning struck the Kingdom of Goryeo.
李成桂从威华岛调动军队
Yi Seong-gye turned back his army from Wihwado.
连崔莹将军也被打败了 您猜怎么着？
General Choe was defeated. There was no other choice.
但是
However,
即便国家处于灭亡状态 也有谋划未来的将帅
they say, even as the country was in ruin,
there was a great general
who made plans for the future.
从内房库收集黄金 从内侍府扫走财宝
He took the gold from the Royal Treasury and Office of Internal Affairs.
坚决不把它交给李成桂
He wouldn't cede the kingdom to Yi Seong-gye.
用其当作军费重建高丽！
And using the treasure his military would rebuild Goryeo.
W-what?
我第一次听说
I'm hearing this for the first time.
当然了
Of course, you are.
因为知道这个秘密的人都死了
Everybody who knows the secret has died.
这就是通往失踪的皇宫宝物的
You have before you the treasure map that leads to that royal treasure.
藏宝图
The one that disappeared.
快给我看看
Now you must show us
您能够嘲笑一万两的胸怀
your boldness that makes a mockery of 10,000 nyang.
这颗大象牙齿是一万两吗？
拥有它吧 绝对是个不错的选择
You should take it. You will not regret it.
让开！
Out of the way!
你这个混蛋！
You son of a--
姜燮你
Kang-seop, damn you!
你在干吗？
What are you doing?
-我问你话呢 -团长 我要疯了
What's going on?
Oh, Captain. Damn it. What do I do?
-这小子 -怎么办？
This bastard.
您怎么来了？
How鈥?How did you鈥?
真是丑陋不堪
You look so extravagant.
我正要
Yes, yes. I was just about to take that鈥?Yes?
解开
So this is, uh鈥?
这就是你当作妹妹一样宠爱的 海浪姑娘吗？
Wait. So this must be the girl you said was your sworn sister.
非常倔强 脾气又暴躁的那个人？
You said you couldn't stand her because she was too stubborn and hot-tempered.
团长
Captain, please鈥?
杀了我吧！
Please just kill me!
我会杀你的
That I will.
你是谁？
And you are?
我是高丽王国最后的公主…
Well, I'm the last princess of the Kingdom of Goryeo--
把他们绑在一起！
Tie them up together!
公主… 放肆！
A princess? How dare you!
-看到了吧？快松绑 -放肆
Hey! Okay. You saw that? Untie me!
天啊 为什么把我绑起来？
- You're tying me up too? How dare you! - Wait.
-倒是给我松绑啊！ -安静点
- Aren't you gonna untie me? - Pipe down!
我们所拥有的一切 都是靠兄弟们的血汗得到的
Everything we have, we earned with the blood of our brothers.
可破了大义离开的禹武治
But Wu Mu-chi broke and discarded that loyalty,
与刚加入团队的小幕勾结
and colluded with Mak-yi, who recently joined us.
不是勾结 我是被绑架了
It wasn't c-collusion, I was kidnapped!
团长在审判
Don't interrupt the captain while she's delivering her judgment!
留下遗嘱吧
Say your last words!
我身为高丽最后的公主…
- My lady, as the last princess of Goryeo-- - I'll judge you separately.
你的判决回头再说
-她是谁？ -真够放肆
- Such impudence. - Who is she anyway?
熊治
Gom-chi.
Gom-chi!
团长 求求您！
Captain, don't! Please!
我还没结婚
Not only have I not married yet, I haven't even held a woman's hand!
从来没有握过女人的手
但是…
So--
熊治哥
- Gom-chi, Gom-chi, Gom-chi!
我出生在倭寇船上
I鈥?I was born on a Japanese pirate ship
只因我是朝鲜人被欺负了十年
and was abused for ten years just because I wasfrom Joseon.
最后我和妈妈逃出来了
My mother and I fled together.
但偏偏被奴隶船抓住了
Too bad you were captured by a slave-trader ship.
在那里又被欺负了十年
I spent another ten years being abused there!
连妈妈也失去了
And even lost my mother.
不要
Gom-chi鈥?
从我开始吧！
I'll go first!
真正的头目不会让下属先走！
A true boss does not let the subordinate go first.
Ooh.
第一次说话像个头目啊
That's the first time you've said anything like a boss!
我送你上路吧
I'll send you first.
抓住他！
Come on!
让开！
Whoo!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on.
都停下来！
Everyone, stop!
尤其是你 弓箭手 不要动
Especially you! Archer, don't you move!
放下弓箭
Lower your bow! I said lower your bow, dammit!
你们团长答应我了！
Your captain promised me!
只要交出这颗象牙 她就不杀我
She said she would spare me if I gave her the tusk!
不是吗？
Didn't you?
它已经在我们手中了
I did, but that tusk already belongs to us.
是吗？
Oh yeah?
但是怎么办？它现在在我手中
You sure? It's in my hands now.
要不 送给龙王吧
On the other hand, you want it in the Dragon King's hands.
不可以！
No!
Stop!
我松手了啊！
I'll let it go!
我真松手了！
I'll really drop it!
Hmm.
-给我 -海浪
Give it.
Hae-rang,
你真打算杀我吗？
Were you really gonna kill me?
是啊
Hmm.
我知道你不会死 因为你藏了把刀
Well, I knew you weren't going to die because you were hiding a knife.
你看到了？
You saw that?
都是大男人了 还又哭又笑的
I see a man who cries then laughs.
果然
Just as I thought, you're prettiest when you're being mean.
你冷冰冰的时候最美
救救我！
Save me!
我们逃跑吧 头目 我再也不想当奴隶了
Let's run away, boss. I can't live as a slave any longer.
你要是没背叛我 你现在就是副团长
You'd be a quartermaster now if you hadn't betrayed me.
-应该好好开火石啊 -你还敢说！
- You should've struck the flint properly. - You!
我都开到手上起泡了
I struck the flint until I got blisters on my hands.
要开到水泡爆开为止啊
You should've struck it until until the blisters burst!
-我要撕了你的嘴 -哥哥
You鈥?you shut your mouth!
-放开我 -他们是在玩
- Mister, they're messing around. - Get off me!
你先放手
好晕哦
高丽军营使用的破译法
Quartermaster, how do you know the Goryeo military way of cracking the code?
你是怎么知道的？
因为我是高丽王国最后的武士
I told you. I was the last warrior of the Kindgom of Goryeo.
阿猫阿狗都是最后的武士
Dogs and cows claim to be the last warrior as well.
光是那些家伙 都能召集百万大军了
If you gather all of them, you'd have a million soldiers.
阿猫阿狗？
Dogs and cows?
干正事
Get on with it!
破好了
That's it.
我开始读了
Let me see what's written.
该死
Dammit.
是暗语
It's a code.
这是只有高丽武官们知道的军营密码
It's an old military cipher only used by Goryeo officers.
最后的武士
Were you a private?
是兵卒吗？
Private Last Warrior?
兵卒 最底部
Private The Very Bottom.
查到了吗？
- What have you found out?
早些时候
I searched for General Joo Bang,
根据内侍府战死者追溯到了将帅朱芳
starting with those who died in battle
from the Office of Internal Affairs.
那天有三者消失
Three things disappeared that day.
第一个是将帅朱芳
- First was General Joo Bang.
第二个是高丽王室的财宝
Second was the treasure of the imperial family of Goryeo
最后一个
- And the last鈥?
是朱芳的妻子
鈥?was Joo Bang's wife.
是啊 朱芳也得有靠山
Of course, Joo Bang must have had someone backing him.
找到他的妻子了吗？
Did you find his wife?
她剪了头发
She shaved her head鈥?
成了修女
- 鈥nd became a Buddhist nun.
看来你搜遍了八道的所有寺庙和庵子
Goodness. You must have searched every temple and hermitage in the country.
所以
What happened?
她说了宝物在哪里吗？
Did she tell you where the treasure is?
在哪里？
So, where鈥?
那个地方
is it?
海吉洞？
"Haegildo"?
无影岩石下的海洞？
"A sea cave beneath a rock with no shadow."
海吉洞？
"Haegildo"?
那条险峻的海路？
Isn't that the p-perilous sea route?
大海还能有多险峻？
The sea is the sea, however perilous it is.
-不懂就别乱说 -有宝物？
- You don't know anything about it. - There's treasure?
那边的水…
The鈥?the water goes--
他住在狭窄的土地上 能知道些什么？
Hey! Since you've lived trapped on that cramped land, you don't know anything.
那个地方
The whirlpools there, they keep swirling, and鈥?
大海里流着漩涡
江河流淌在海上啊
A river flows under the ocean!
屎就是屎 屁就是屁
Poop is poop and farts are farts.
江河怎么会流淌在海上？
How can a river flow under the sea?
就是在流淌啊！
I'm telling you it flows!
你这小子
Why you little--
流淌
It flows!
-流淌 -也是
- It flows, it flows. - Forgive me.
拉稀屎确实会流淌
There's diarrhea too.
问题是不知道这条河有多长
The problem is that we don't know how long the river is.
没有人被卷走后脱身成功
In other words, no one's gone under and come out the other end.
那我就不去了 放弃
Well, then I'm not going. I give up. I give up.
团长 咱别去了
Captain, let's not go.
-副团长 -在
- First mate! - Yes?
把船停到岸边 抓十头猪来
Bring the boat to shore and catch ten pigs.
是
- Yes.
- Raise the sails!
扬帆起航！
使劲拉！
如果你说的是事实
If what you're saying is true,
那的确是巨大的宝物
it surely is an amazing amount of treasure.
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want in return?
请您成为朝鲜的国王
Become the king of Joseon.
Yah!
你呢？
And you?
我要成为耽罗之王
I want to be the king of Tamna.
一路平安啊 头目！
Enjoy your trip, Boss!
一路平安！
Bye!
路上保重！
那个漩涡是什么？
Oh no. What is that whirpool, huh?
Whoa!
海下流淌的江河不知尽头
There's no way of knowing where the river under the sea ends.
千万别弄丢那个包袱
Do not let go of your pouch.
Yah! Yah!
说不定会死 你不害怕吗？
You said we might die. Are you afraid?
胆小者不该带领团队
Someone so afraid shouldn't be a leader.
老大要怕死才行
Uh鈥?
A leader who's afraid can find a
way for us all to survive together.
那样才会寻找共同生存之道
就是为了共同生存才冒着生命危险
We're risking our lives to survive together.
- Yeah. Sure.
团长
Captain, our boat will be swept away if we go any closer to it.
再靠近的话 船可能被水冲走了
-我们从这里乘河流 -什么？
We'll ride the current from here!
-我们走！ -是！
- Let's go! - Yes, Captain!
-走！ -从这里？
什么味道？
- Ugh. What's this smell? - Go on!
是你们精心擦拭的猪膀胱
They're the pigs bladders that you washed so earnestly.
往里面填满了空气
They're filled with air.
难怪有臊味
- I thought it smelled like piss. - I didn't wash mine thoroughly.
我刚刚没擦干净呢
我好怕 哥哥
I'm so scared, mister.
不行！
No, don't!
你先走吧 我不行了
- You go first.
I can't make it.
快走吧 你这个混蛋！
Hurry up and go, you bastard!
我在这里守着船！
Don't worry! I'll take care of the boat!
你们快去快回！
Have a safe trip!
起来
Get up.
咬紧牙
Clench your teeth.
小幕呢？
Mak-yi?
这小子
脏死了
真臭
That stinks!
团长 这里也没有
Captain, it's not here either.
真是的 宝物到底在哪里？
Really? Just where is the treasure.
哎呀 该死的
I mean, really.
团长
Captain!
没有其他路 全被堵上了
There isn't another path! It's completely blocked off!
没有路也没有宝物
Look harder!
团长 接下来怎么办？
Captain, what's next?
我就怕这样才想卖地图的
This is why I wanted to sell the map, in case this happened.
我以为海浪会有点本领 但她跟那些白痴一样啊
I thought Hae-rang would be different,
还被那个假地图给骗了
but she's just the same as those fools getting tricked by a fake map.
-好饿 -喂 那边也没有吗？
- It's not here either? - Ugh. I'm hungry!
这里也没有
Hey. It's not there either?
-都集合吧 -集合
Hey. Gather around.
-快点 -快集合
Get over here, quickly! He said gather around.
话都说到这份上了
I'm saying it because it came up. If we had sold the map, where would we be?
如果按照我所说 当时卖掉了地图
-他又开始了 -我没说错啊
- Shut up! - I'm not wrong.
团长 要不要再找找？
What should we do? Should we check again?
各位打算怎么办啊？
Okay, okay, okay. What are you gonna do?
你们都只是盯着团长的嘴
They're all waiting for your next order.
既然冒着生命危险带过来
You risked our lives bringing us here, hmm?
无论是绝望
Whether you give them despair or hope,
还是希望
头儿应该负责到底
the leader needs to take responsibility.
海浪 你不是这里的头儿吗？
Hey, Hae-rang. A leader must鈥?
那必须得动动脑
must use their brain. Yeah?
Huh? Did he鈥?
竟敢拔团长的头发
How dare you touch the captain's head!
-看好了 -你这个混蛋！
- Watch closely. - You bastard!
搞什么？
What?
那是什么？
What the hell is that?
终于出来了
How will he kill him?
你死定了
Now you're a goner.
还以为你是头目吗？
You still think you're the boss.
你都没有刀 还能怎么做？
Too bad you don't have your sword.
我从来没输过赤手空拳的战斗
Never in my life have I lost a fistfight.
我也是
Neither have I.
-熊治！ -大哥
Gom-chi!
真粗鲁
- Such imeciles.
我发现路被钟乳石挡住了
I discovered this path that was blocked by a stalactite.
头儿
Captain,
先请
please go ahead.
你生气啦？
Hey. You upset?
-生气了吧？ -好累
You all right?
-一起走啊 -真是的
团长
Whoo!
Captain.
找到了！
What?
这一个顶一百匹丝绸
You could by 100 rolls of silk with just one of these.
-建十座宫殿也绰绰有余 -就是啊
- It's enough to build ten palaces! - I know!
让开
Move.
- Hmm? - Out of the way.
He's acting all haughty again.
太失望了
- I'm a bit disappointed.
我觉得很好啊
Why? I'm happy with it.
为什么只有银瓶？
Why are there only silver bottles?
金片才是高丽王室的宝物之最
The royal treasure should have gold pieces.
金片？
Gold pieces?
这么点儿银瓶箱也就值…
A box of these silver bottles would be worth鈥?
一块金片吧
one piece of gold.
那个金片总共有多少块？
How many gold pieces should there be?
这么小的东西
About this big and this much.
大概这么多？
这么多？
This much.
This鈥?
据说是填满了高丽王室的内房库
It's said that it filled up the entire Royal Treasury of Goryeo's palace.
寻找金片！
We must find the gold!
Find the gold pieces!
都给我搜！
- Hurry! - Over there!
快去找吧
You aren't lying, are you?
不是开玩笑吧？
I'm honorable. I'm Wu Mu-chi.
把我看成什么人了 我可是禹武治
这是
What is this?
什么？
This isn't a flag they use in military camps.
这不是军营里使用的旗帜
乍一看像鬼怪的脸
At first glance, it looks like the face of a goblin,
-但仔细看… -如何？
but when you look at it up close鈥?
When you look at it up close?
不清楚
I have no idea.
让开
Get out of the way.
发生地震了！
It's an earthquake!
-团长 地震了 -快点搬
Captain, it's an earthquake!
阿贵和熊治回船上去拿更多的绳子
A-gwi, Gom-chi, go back to the boat and bring more rope.
是 熊治 快跟我来！
Yes, captain. Gom-chi, hurry! Follow me!
快点行动！
躲开！
Everyone, get back!
有人来了
Someone's here.
停
Halt.
Yes, sir.
你也搬啊
- Huh? - Help move these.
这是什么？这不是航海图吗？
Wait. Isn't this a鈥?a sea chart?
航海图？
What? A map?
朝鲜 倭国
Joseon, Japan.
这是
And h-here is
-稻妻岛 -什么岛？
Inazuma Island.
Inazu鈥?w-what鈥?zuma?
往池塘跑！
Run back to the pond!
加快速度 快点！
Hurry up! Come on, quickly!
-团长呢？ -洞穴深处
- What about the captain? - Still in the cave.
搞什么？
What the鈥?
-还好吗？ -疼死了
- You okay? - Ah, it hurts, dammit!
团长
Captain! Captain!
赶紧带团长离开！
Get the captain out of here!
抓住他们！
Get them!
禹武治
Wu Mu-chi.
你这该死的盗贼！
You bandit scum!
我是来自耽罗的军官夫兴秀
Officer Bu Heung-su of Tamna.
过来报告斩敌将之首的功劳
Reporting the successful decapitation of the enemy general.
整备队伍 准备夜袭
Prepare for battle! We attack them at nightfall.
请听令！
Reporting!
请护送伤兵 搭建营地
I have a direct order! Evacuate the wounded and make camp.
敌营就在眼前 趁夜色突袭的话…
The enemy line is closeby. We ambush them tonight and--
请听令
It's an order!
先护送伤兵 搭建营地…
Evacuate the wounded first and make camp--
回去转告这里没有伤兵
Deliver the message that we have no wounded.
在我的军队里
There are only two kinds of men in my unit.
只有战士和死者
Fighting or dead.
你杀了伤兵并继续前进了吗？
You marched on after killing the wounded?
战争不就是这样的吗？
Isn't that how war is?
你亲手杀了你的手下？
You killed your own men with your own hands?
不过我带来了敌将的头
In exchange, I offer the general's head.
主上殿下答应过你
His Majesty promised to make you king of Tamna
若砍下敌将的头 就让你成为耽罗王吧？
if you brought him the enemy's head, correct?
你很了解嘛
What of it?
禽兽不如者不能任其为王
I won't allow a man like you to become king.
我将依照军法处决你
You'll be punished according to military law.
捆绑夫兴秀！
Arrest and bind him, now!
-是！ -是！
Yes, sir!
你这个肮脏的盗贼
You dirty thief.
你想杀掉我 夺走我的功劳吗？
You'll kill me and take credit for my success?
-把剑放下 -我决不让出我的功劳！
- Lower your sword. - I don't intend to hand the credit to you!
该死
Again a mistake.
你需要宝物吗？
So you need treasure, do you?
Watch out!
你走一步 我就扔一箱
Another one goes in for each step you take.
你又要偷走我的东西吗？
Will you steal what is mine, you aging thief?
要是你还贪得无厌的话
If you still covet what is out of your reach.
要不是因为你
If not for you and your men,
我早就成为国王了
I would've already been a king.
国王？
A king?
连禽兽都不如的人当什么王？
How can someone who's lower than a beast be a king?
下地狱吧！
You can go to hell!
宝物！
Whoa, whoa!
The treasure!
Whoa!
大哥！
Captain!
对不起
Sorry.
怎么不上来？
Why aren't they coming up?
团长不会出事了吧？
Do you think something happened to the captain?
我得下去看看
I better go down there.
The rope!
-抓绳子了 -快点
- Come on! - Get them up!
-拉上来！ -拉上来！
Pull!
团长！
Captain!
头目！
Boss!
谢谢你 团长
Thank you, Captain.
走好 头目
Farewell, Boss.
一定去了好地方
She's gone to a better place.
航海图去哪儿了？
Where did the sea chart go?
团长呢？
Where's the captain?
那边
- Huh?
Whoa!
不是那边 是这边！
Not that way! This way, this way!
等等 宝物呢？
Wait, wait! What about the silver?
鲸鱼
- The whale! The whale! - Whale?
是宝物！
不是这个
No! Not this!
把宝物吐出来
Give us the treasure!
大哥 这是什么？
What's that, Captain?
原来是航海图
It was a sea chart.
我正在收拾东西
I thought I should sort some of your things.
你偷了很多嘛
Seems like you're stealing as well.
我没有偷 只是收拾的时候
I'm not stealing them, I was just sorting them out.
这些东西总是粘在一起
- These just got all tangled together.
身体好点了吗？
How are you feeling, Captain?
托你的福 头也开始疼了
Thanks to you my head hurts now.
话说这些衣服又特别又好看
These clothes are really quite pretty, but strange.
西域大海里有很多奇怪的东西
There are a lot of unusual things in western seas.
这里只有我一个女人
I'm the only woman on board,
这段时间积攒的东西都堆满了仓库
so everything I've gathered is piled up in the storage.
挑你喜欢的穿吧
You can wear whatever you want.
您好好休息吧
Then please get some rest.
你腰上缠上的东西
The things hanging from my belt,
是先牺牲的兄弟们的遗物
they were inherited from brothers who've already died.
对我来说比什么都珍贵
They are my prized possessions.
天呐
Oh dear.
Oh crap.
拿去
They're yours.
我会尽忠的
I pledge my loyalty--
尽忠什么
What loyalty?
只是互相依靠罢了
We find ourselves in the same situation.
所以必须相互坦诚
That's why we should be honest with each other.
既然上了同一条船 你也依靠大家吧
I hope you realize that you can depend on us.
不要一个人费心思
Don't struggle on your own.
没关系 我们都是女贼嘛
What does it matter between two thieving women?
总从哪儿掉呢
These just keep falling out of nowhere.
都干什么呢 天亮了
What are you doing? The sun's up.
鲷儿 你少喝点酒
Do-mi, you better stop drinking so much.
身体怎么样？
You okay?
瞅什么？
What?
宝物有那么好吗？死了就都没了
Do you love treasure that much? You could've died out there.
是大家都想要的
We all wanted it, Mu-chi.
要是赌上我的命可以得到它 就不觉得可惜
It's worth it, even if getting it means risking my life.
命都没了 拿到它又有什么用？
What will you do with it once you have it?
算了
Stop it!
你又不懂
You wouldn't understand.
我不懂什么？
What would I not understand?
我们都是同舟共济的家人
We're a big family out here on the ocean.
不只是船上有家人
But the ship isn't the only place where family is.
船外也有
We have family elsewhere.
有先死者的家人
The family of those who've died before us,
也有新的家人会加入
and more family to come in the future.
现在的我
Right now鈥?
帮不了他们
there's nothing I can do for those people.
是身为团长要肩负的责任吗？
Is that your responsibility as captain?
这可真是
That's some鈥?
头疼啊
pain in the neck.
问你一个问题
I want to know!
你为什么认为宝物会是金片？
Why did you think the treasure would be gold pieces?
如果像象牙上写的那样 足以重建高丽的话
If the tusk is right and it's supposed to be enough to rebuild Goryeo,
那得是内房库的金片才行
it would be all the gold pieces in the Royal Treasury.
-金片？ -你把那个鬼怪旗帜放哪儿了？
- Gold pieces? - And what about that goblin flag?
在洞里呗
It's back in the cave.
调头
Turn around. We're going back to the cave to get the flag.
返回洞穴 拿回旗帜
-什么？ -嗯？
- What? - Huh?
那个旗帜的反面是航海图
That flag is an inverted sea chart.
说不定是隐藏内房库黄金的
A sea chart?
It might be a map to the treasure,
藏宝图
to the Royal Treasury's gold.
藏宝图？
调头！
Turn the ship around! Turn the ship around!
快行动！
No. No!
不是的
No, no, no, no, no, no.
-不是？ -你是谁？
- No? - No?
不用回去了
There's no need to go back.
-您哪位？ -赶紧交出来啊
- What are you doing? - Just hand it over.
-什么？ -你拿了鬼怪旗帜嘛
- Hand what over? - You have it, the goblin flag.
你说什么？
What was that?
不是的
I don't.
- What? Hey!
- You鈥?
把它藏哪儿了？
Where did you hide it?
-等等 -把它藏哪儿了？
- Wait a minute! - Where did you hide it?
为什么从我这找藏宝…
Fine! The treasure鈥?
翻他身子
Search him!
-过来 臭小子 -扒掉衣服
- Come here, you!
-扒光他 -丢了 我弄丢了！
- Strip off all his clothes. - I lost it!
干脆杀掉我吧
Just kill me instead!
我们小幕吃了不少苦头吧
You must be having a rough time, huh?
团长
- Captain, please.
-真可怜 -我太难了
- You poor thing. - It's been so hard.
- Blow.
你们都太坏了
Have some heart. How could you be so cruel to Mak-yi?
太坏了
Make it stop. End this cruelty.
So cruel.
我们小幕看过地图吧
The goblin map. You saw it, right?
你看到类似标记点的东西吗？
Did you happen to see any of the markings?
Yes.
位置呢？
The location?
稻妻岛
The island of Inazuma.
什么？
What "ma"?
翻译过来就是
In our language, it's, um, "Beongaesum."
-闪电岛 -闪电岛？
- Beongaesum? - Beongaes--.
闪电
- Hey.
喂
你说的是那个闪电岛吗？
Wait. The Beongaesum from the stories?
每天都会出现数千次雷云
Are you joking?
Storm clouds rain down lightning
there 1,000 times a day.
每打一次闪电
Every time it comes down, it's ten years' worth of lightning in one go,
就有十年的量噼里啪啦打下来
十年的量？皮痒痒了吧
like pop, pop, pop!
Ten years worth? Bullshit!
我是说真的
Hey. It's true, okay?
那个地方在哪？
Where is it, then?
我也只是听说过 还没去过
I've only heard of it. I've never been there.
你没去过还说什么 臭小子？
- Never been there?
是真的
- You little-- - He's not lying.
原来团长您去过
Oh. So you've been there, Captain?
有时整个天空都会布满闪电
Sometimes, the whole sky fills up with lightning as far as the eye can see.
-看来会很壮观 -我也没有看过
It sounds like quite the spectacle.
I've never actually seen it either.
偏偏是闪电岛
It had to be Beongaesum.
船帆会被旋风撕裂
Swirling winds rip the sails,
桅杆也会被雷劈断
the lightning snaps the mast.
简直是人间地狱
It's a living hell among hells.
你听谁说的？
And who told you that?
我可是生于海的海人
Despite how I look, I'm a man of the oceans.
出生在倭寇船上 从吸母乳开始
I was born on a pirate ship, traveling the oceans since suckling my mother's breast.
就在各个海域游荡
等一下
Hang on.
那你知道路吧？
That means you know the way?
天呐
Jeez鈥?
真可笑
This is ridiculous.
Woohoo!
那个是什么？
What is that big, bad boy?
据说是明太祖为了讨伐倭寇
That's the Fire Dragon Cannon
that the Emperor Hongwu bestowed upon King Gongmin
而赐给恭愍王的火龙炮
to suppress the Japanese pirates.
我们不是要去寻宝吗？
Weren't we after treasure?
海里只有倭寇吗？
There's more than just Japanese pirates.
还有那些海盗
Yeah. Those other pirate bastards.
大哥
Captain, if I may,
我想试试那个大家伙
I'm gonna give this bad boy a try.
我也一起去
- Me too!
那么喜欢杀生吗？
Do you like killing that much?
那不就是活着的乐趣嘛
Isn't that the joy of life?
让开
Out of the way. Out of the way!
走开
Get out!
随着乌云
With a blanket of dark clouds, the entire sky is filled with lightning,
满天闪电
like zap, zap, zap, zap, zap.
噼里啪啦
所以到底在哪里？
So where is this exactly, huh?
怎么总打断我？这样下去要熬夜了
Will you quit interrupting? We'll be up all night at this rate.
-臭小子 -团长
- This bastard! - Whoa! Captain!
你怎么老打断话！
Stop cutting him off!
好
Okay.
我说到哪儿了？
Where was I?
反正那个地方去不得 去了就会死
Anyway, we can't go there. We'll definitely die if we do.
知道了 你说的话都听懂了
Okay, I understand. So why don't you just tell us just the location. All right?
赶紧说位置吧 好吗？
- Hmm? - I told you we'll all die.
会死的
You're a good boy. Right, Mak-yi?
听话啊 小幕 我不会去的
就告诉我位置吧
We won't go. So tell me, where is it?
既然不去 还问位置干吗？
If you're not going, why do you need the location?
臭小子
- This bastard!
真憋得慌
- Give me a sword. I'll just kill him now. - Here, Captain.
给我一把刀 我要杀了他
给您
咱别去了 团长
Let's not go there, Captain.
那片海太汹涌了 仅凭勇气是不行的
Those waters sound too dangerous to cross with mere courage.
就是
Yeah. That's what I'm saying.
别的地方就算了 但如果是怕海
To be afraid of the sea, of all places, you can't call yourself a pirate. Can you?
-那还算海盗吗？ -那是渔夫
我们是海盗 海盗即大海！
He's a fisherman.
We are pirates, and the
open sea is our domain!
黄金在等着我们！
The gold is waiting for us!
-走 我们去寻宝！ -我们走！
No one can stop us, not even ourselves!
- To find the treasure!
Let's go!
若带我们去闪电岛
If you guide us to Bongaesum,
就把十分之一的宝物给你
you can keep a tenth of the treasure there.
Why would we give it to him?
死后黄金有什么用？
Give it to me now, while I'm still alive.
如果想给 就在死前给
If I'm dead, what good is gold?
你有什么想要的吗？
Is there something else?
这条船上能有值得拿命换的东西吗？
There's nothing here worth exchanging your life for?
并不是没有
Well, it's not that there isn't anything I want.
但也不会给我的
It's not like you're going to give it to me, so鈥?
那是什么？
What is it, then?
那个…
It's鈥?
不好开口
I can't bring myself to say it.
说说看
What is it? Say it!
-只有我一个人知道路线 -是啊
- Only I know how to get there. - Yes, indeed.
-只有我去过那里 -知道
- Only I have been there. - We know, we know.
那样的话
With that in mind鈥?See鈥?
吓我一跳
I got it!
看来你想当团长
You want to become the captain.
- What?
因为生前一直受欺负是一种耻辱
It's unfair for me to die after being treated like this.
就算是找到宝物之前也好
So just at least until we find the treasure,
海盗王…
Pirate King.
这个疯子 你找死吧！
Are you mad? Do you want a swift death?
放下
Put it down.
决定权
Shouldn't
交给团长吧？
the captain decide?
怎么了？
Well?
Ah.
作为团长
As a captain you can risk your life, but you can't give up your authority, huh?
可以舍弃生命 但舍弃不了权势吗？
我问大家
I'll ask everyone!
只有二选一
You can choose one or the other.
一 答应小幕的请求并寻宝
Shall we go find the treasure after fulfilling Mak-yi's request?
二 立即杀了这家伙并整顿纪律
Or shall we kill him right now to maintain order?
如果想要宝物
Those of you who want the treasure
就举手吧
raise your hand.
团长
Come on, Captain.
你应该闭上眼睛
You need to close your eyes.
妈妈
Mother,
我成了海盗王
I am the Pirate King.
我向龙王请安
Let me greet the Dragon King!
我是新任海盗王
I am the new鈥?
小幕！
Pirate King, Mak-yi!
团长
Captain,
这种事就交给手下吧
uh, leave this kind of chore to your subordinates. All right?
就当是放几天假 好好休息休息
Think of it as a vacation for a few days, and take a break.
团长在握着舵轮
Dammit!
The captain is the one
manning the helm, of course.
请叫我浪儿 副团长
So just call me Rang, the quartermaster.
团长 别这样啊
Come on, Captain!
快到晚饭时间了
It's almost dinnertime.
都出去吧
Off you go!
团长 您现在这个样子
I mean, how could we possibly do anything
我们心里也不好受…
when you're down here working, Captain?
出去！
Get out, dammit!
-请 -是 浪儿
Please.
你说浪儿？
Okay, okay, Rang.
- Rang? Did you say Rang?
- Come on. She seems upset.
她生气啦？
Big time.
-非常生气 -她非常在乎权威
She's sensitive about the situation
-其实也就几天 -那也是啊
even though it's only for a few days.
被黄金蒙蔽了双眼 举手的家伙都死定了
Even if it's only for a few days, they're all blinded by the gold.
Dammit! I'll kill the
ones who raised their hands!
-干吗打我？ -你睁眼了吧？
- Why are you hitting me? - You kept your eyes open.
振作起来
Chin up, yeah?
浪儿
Rang.
我反倒觉得如释重负
As far as I'm concerned, I really felt relieved.
你呢？
How about you?
不过如今这世道 有钱就是好
Hey. Money is the real boss these days, you know?
你是输给黄金了 谁赢得了黄金啊
You just lost against gold. How do you win against gold, hmm?
不要太在意
- Don't mind it too much.
别得瑟
Tread carefully.
我不在乎权力
It's not about the position.
只要够资格 我随时都可以让步
I was willing to give it up if there was anyone worthy.
什么资格？
Worthy how?
幕团长 吃饭吧！
Captain Mak-yi, time to eat!
-我是谁？ -新团长
- Who am I? - The new captain.
您是新团长
New captain, sir.
以后不要让我闻到任何腥味
From now on, no fishy food on my plate.
给我端上一只炖鸡和浊酒
- Bring me a cooked chicken and rice wine.
喂 团长
Hey, captain?
半月岛在右边呢
Halfmoon Island is on the right.
不是说要从它右侧经过吗？
Didn't you say to make a left here?
这个白痴
You're a moron.
看到岛就应该立刻回报给我！
Why didn't you tell me when you saw it?
我刚爬上来
But I just got up here.
你早干吗了才爬上去？
Why couldn't you get up there sooner?
因为刚才某人站在这里了
Because someone was standing up here until now,
沉浸在自己的世界里
acting all cool and showing off.
今天别给他食物
Don't give him any food.
给懒人一个鱿鱼都是浪费
Even old squid is wasted on that fool.
你今天饿一餐试试
No food for you. Eat that!
把这里擦干净了
- Jerk. - Hey. Wipe here.
可以了 走开
That's enough. Get lost.
-你 -怎么了？
- Hey, Witless. - Yeah?
你也上去
Go up there too.
一个人就够了啊
Isn't one person enough?
太阳落山后什么也看不到啊
You can't really see once the sun sets anyway.
-我们还要吃晚饭 -吃晚饭…
- We need to have dinner, Captain. - I'm hungry.
可以上去吃啊！
You'll eat your dinner up there with that other moron!
人怎么会变成那样 要死了
How could he change that much? It's pissing me off.
-你嘟囔什么？ -什么也没说
- What are you muttering about? - I didn't say anything.
Yeah!
这个不得了啊
You are incredible!
用沙丁鱼怎么能做出这种味道？
Hey. How did you鈥?did you make sardines taste like this?
并非所有的沙丁鱼都是一样的
Not all sardines are the same.
若了解这大海的味道 便可以做出这种美味
Ocean flavors, if you know them, you can draw the real flavor like this.
I knew you had good cooking skills.
我知道你手艺好
Wow!
但没想到是这种程度
But I never expected it to be this good. Seriously!
Mmm!
这肯定是团长做的
Hey. The Captain should not be cooking!
团长的制作秘诀是什么？
She's better as a captain than a chef!
吃完了
I finished it! All of it!
慢慢吃 以后经常给你做
Take your time eating. I'll make it often from now on.
Huh?
Mmm!
真的很严重 我都没法睡
I'm telling you it's very serious
I can't sleep.
过来一下
Come over here.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
床腿都断…
The legs of the bed are all bro鈥?ken.
修好了
All fixed now.
告辞
Good. Excuse me.
你为什么修这个？
- Why would you fix the bed, Rang? - Why not me?
为什么这么问？
你知道弄断这些有多难吗？
Do you have any idea how hard it was to break all of those?
Huh?
我真是活不下去了 为什么修啊
Seriously鈥?I mean, why did you鈥?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
算了
It's okay.
不过借给我那个吧 红色的
Could you help me out and let me borrow that red stuff?
你涂嘴唇的那个东西
The thing you put on your lips.
我怎么会有那种东西
I have no such thing.
You know. Come on.
你和武治哥在厨房干活的时候 经常涂的那个…
When you're around Mu-chi in the kitchen, and you put it on to--
浪儿在吗？
Rang, are you there?
-叫我出来是想让我看这个吗？ -怎么样？
Did you ask me here to see this?
You like it?
是啊
I forgot
夜空总是如此美丽
the night sky was always so beautiful.
不过你往头发上抹什么了？
What did you put in your hair?
抹什么？
My hair?
因为没洗头 所以出油了
Uh, it's oily from not washing it.
用了我麻油的小子是谁！
Who the hell was it?
Who touched my sesame oil?
有人找你
They're looking for you.
浪儿
Rang,
你懂爱情吗？
what do you know of love?
那是我的私事
That's personal.
Huh?
是私事呢
What are you talking about, personal?
每个人的爱都不一样
Love means something different for everyone.
就像海浪的大小不同
Just like waves of different sizes.
那么去妓院和妓女分享的爱
Then is love you give to courtesans a big wave or a small wave?
是巨浪还是小浪？
-我就喝了点酒 -算了
- I only drank there. - Yeah. Sure.
我真的只喝酒了
I only drank. I swear.
副团长姜燮…
Your quartermaster, Kang-seop鈥?
我问你了吗？
I don't recall asking about that.
我真的只喝酒了
Really, I only drank.
-是姜燮… -我先下去了
- Kang-seop-- - I'm going back down.
浪儿
Rang.
浪儿 等等 你看看这个
Rang, wait. Take a look at this.
浪儿
Rang.
“意图深邃胜海渊 勇气隐匿于黑暗”
"Meaning is as deep as the sea, but courage is hidden in the dark.
“穿越刹那之流光 追寻真理的光芒”
Pass by the flash of light and find the light of the truth."
这是什么意思 大哥？
What does it mean, captain?
解开这个谜底才能找到宝物
We have to solve this riddle in order to find the treasure.
惩治逆贼的时候才会进行枭首
Impaling the head on a spike is a punishment usually reserved for traitors.
这十二个人会是谁呢 大哥？
Do you know who these 12 men are, captain?
海水沸腾了！
The sea is boiling!
什么？海水沸腾了？
What? The sea is boiling?
那是什么？
What's that?
乌云马上要来了
Dark clouds will roll in soon.
-赶紧把船帆折起来 -是
We must fold the sails, now.
-快把船帆折起来 -折起船帆
Fold the sails! Fold the sails!
时机还没到！
Not yet!
时机未到 先别动
- Don't do it yet. - Not until I say so.
搞不好会流入火海之中…
If we mistime it, we'll be swept into the Sea of Fire!
向您汇报 团长
Trust me, Captain.
我说
Do tell.
前团长不知道闪电岛 怎么会知道火海呢？
How does the former captain not know Bongaesum,
小时候被暴风雨卷进去过
but knows the Sea of Fire?
I was swept into it by
a rainstorm when I was young.
这升腾的水汽和当年一样
And this rising haze looks just like it did then.
穿过闪电岛之后才会出现火海
The Sea of Fire appears after passing Bongaesum.
但即使是鬼也会死在那里
Even a ghost would die there,
你活着出来了？
but you survived?
我活着出来才会在这里啊
I wouldn't be standing here if I hadn't.
据说火海中有成百上千的龙
I've heard that hundreds of thousands of dragons live in the Sea of Fire, so鈥?
你看到龙了吗？
You've seen a dragon?
实际上那不是龙 而是火柱
When you see it for real,
it's not dragons, but huge pillars of fire.
成百上千的火柱破海冲天
Hundreds and thousands of pillars of fire piercing the sea
and surging into the sky!
乌云要靠近了！
The black clouds are rolling in!
必须马上折起船帆
We must hurry and fold the sails.
失去船帆 就会失去一切
If we lose the sails, we lose everything!
时机未到！
I just said not yet!
这个路我熟
I know the way.
Huh?
躲开！
Everyone out of the way!
是闪电！
Lightning!
快把帆折起来 把船舶下角合上！
Quickly fold the sails and batten down the hatches!
折起船帆！
Fold the sails!
躲开！
Get out!
别抬头 我们都会死的！
Keep your heads down! We're all gonna die!
团长
Captain!
幕团长 赶紧握舵轮啊 只有你知道路！
Captain Mak-yi, take the wheel! You know the way!
幕团长！
Captain Mak-yi! The wheel is spinning by itself!
舵轮自己转呢！
快上去！
Captain Mak-yi, go quickly!
幕团长 快点上去啊！
在这里都会死的 都躲到甲板下面！
We'll all die up here!
Get below deck!
Go down! Go down!
水满就死定了 不能下去！
If the boat fills with water, you'll all die!
Don't go below deck!
上去！
Get back up! Get back up!
用绳子把自己绑起来！
Tie yourself with rope.
幕团长 赶紧指挥啊！
Captain Mak-yi, give the order!
就那么做吧！
Do that! Do that!
船舶破损就逃不掉了 不要绑起来 要抓住！
If the ship wrecks, you won't be able to escape!
Don't tie yourself! Just hold on!
抓住！
Hold on!
全员听从浪儿的话！
Everyone, follow Rang's orders!
只要你闭嘴就行了 禹武治！
If you just keep your mouth shut it'd be fine Wu Mu-chi!
原来是这样的啊 大哥！
That's what they're for, captain?
不愧是大哥！
As expected of our captain!
抓紧了！
Hold on tight!
救救我！
Help me!
快把帆折起来 把船舶下角合上！
Quickly fold the sails and batten down the hatches!
动作快点！
Quickly! Go!
这哪是十年的量？是一万年！
This isn't ten years' worth of lightning! It's like 10,000 years'!
别怂了 握住我的脖子！
Pull yourself together! Grab my neck.
不是那里
Not like that.
救命！
- Help! - Save us!
Ah, shit!
What?
这是天堂 还是地狱啊
This is it! We're finally here!
救命 这里有人！
Save us! We're over here!
救命！
Save us!
看到闪电要避远 第一次见闪电吗？
After the first lightning strike, you get out of the way?
明明是自己躲得最快
Your first storm, huh?
-快下去 -一群傻瓜
He was the first to run away, dammit!
- Get off!
- You're all idiots!
幕团长 宝物在哪里？
Captain Mak-yi, where's the treasure?
现在开始找啊 都没有地图了
We have to find it. We don't have the map.
什么？
What?
真是的 鼠粪般大的岛 随便挖也能挖出来吧
It's a small island. If we dig around, we'll stumble across it.
鼠粪？鼠粪有这么大吗？
Small? You call this small?
找死啊
I ought to kill this fool.
怎么都盯着我？行动啊
What? Why are you all staring at me, huh?
因为你是头儿啊
You're the leader.
给我什么待遇了？
When did you treat me like one?
有人乖乖听我的话吗？
Not one of you ever followed my orders, dammit!
都在背后骂我
You all talk behind my back,
又苦又危险的事情都让我出面
then put me on the spot when things got dangerous?
这是奴隶好不好！
It's like being a damn slave!
那才是头儿 你不知道吗？
That's what being a leader is. You didn't know?
-是的 -没错
He's right.
要疯了
That's insane.
好 你们等着
Right. Just a moment.
-想起来了 -怎么了？
- He remembers. - What is it?
我不想当头儿了
I quit being the leader.
真想砍掉你的头
- I'll crush his head! I'm serious!
是闪电岛！
Bongaesum ahoy!
Where?
-走 -正在走
Let go of me! Let go! I'm walking!
头目 这是陆地 不是大海
Boss, this is the land, not the ocean.
海中有龙 陆上有虎
The dragon is master at sea, but the tiger is on land.
从今以后 我海盗王小幕
So, now I, Mak-yi, the Pirate King鈥?
小幕会服从您的命令
鈥ill follow your orders.
幕团长 我离开陆地 跟随大海很久了
I've been away at sea too long, Captain.
副团长 你知道路线吗？
Quartermaster, you dare to lead the way
知道路线的幕团长在后面呢
when Captain Mak-yi, who knows the way, is behind you?
还不快跑过来 幕团长？
Come here, Captain Mak-yi, in three, two鈥?
一 二
这边
It's over there.
你在找什么？
Looking for something?
河流
A stream of water.
不愧是团长啊
You sure are a natural leader.
朱芳应该也会这么做
Joo Bang would have done the same.
快点！
Hurry!
这些人一直住在这里
These folks sure rest peacefully here.
难怪没有人见过消失的朱芳
This is why no one's seen Joo Bang since he disappeared.
话说 大哥解开了那个谜底吗？
By the way, did you solve the riddle, Captain?
“意图深邃胜海渊 勇气隐匿于黑暗”
"Meaning is as deep as the sea, courage is hidden in the dark.
“穿越刹那之流光”
Pass by the flash of light and find the light of the truth."
“追寻真理的光芒”
还要挖吗？
There's nothing here.
有疑虑就别挖了
If you're not gonna trust me, stop digging!
闪电只击相同的地方
The lightning is striking the same place.
现在
Now!
是吧？
- Hmm. - See?
击打相同的地方
It strikes the same place over and over.
怀疑的时候又击打
Just when you think it's done, it--
就是现在
There! Right now.
Whoa.
难道有东西？
Is there something there?
-看样子是有 -会是什么呢？
- It seems like it. - But what?
-去看看？ -去瞧瞧？
- Shall we see? - Shall we?
不要挖那边 要挖这个地方
- Don't dig there. Dig right here.
还要挖吗？
Should we dig more?
-再挖点 -再？
- Dig more. - More?
就一点点
Just a little bit more.
挖得很深嘛
Ugh. Dammit.
Wow. Look at all you've dug!
一群白痴 让你们挖 还挖那么深
These morons just keep digging because I told them to?
还要挖吗？
找到了
Something's here!
-找到了 -在哪儿？
- He found something.
等那个小子来了就埋里面
Let's bury him here when he comes over.
活埋吗？
- Alive? - Hey.
找到了吗？
You鈥?you've found something?
抓住那个小子！
- Treasure. - Get that son of a bitch!
-臭小子 别跑 -抓住那个小子！
Get that bastard, dammit!
我自己过去吧
I'll go on my own.
黄金是个好东西啊
Gold is truly amazing.
什么？
Hmm?
第一次看你主动出面
I've never seen you doing something without someone ordering you to.
因为你想要嘛
It's because you want it.
要不是因为你 我都不会来这里
If it weren't for you, I wouldn't be here.
我也不会留在那该死的海上
Or stayed on that damned sea at all.
第一次见到你时
The first time I saw you,
我以为是阴间使者来接我的
I thought you were the angel of death coming for my soul.
我很心动
My heart fluttered
与你同行的阴间路
thinking of a death with you.
即使死了也很开心
I was happy to be dying.
饿的时候吃吧
Eat this if you're hungry.
这个
Wow! This, uh鈥?
-这不是人间美味嘛 -嗯
Delicious.
Hmm.
Mmm.
谢谢
Thanks so much.
不客气
Don't mention it.
叛徒
"Traitors."
找对地方了
We've come to the right place.
李成桂
Yi Seong-gye.
郑道传
Jeong Do-jeon.
那边是左侍中曹敏修大人
And that's Left State Counselor Cho Min-su.
朝鲜的开国功臣们
All the founders of Joseon are all gathered here.
原来都聚在这里
Those were the twelve traitors of Goryeo.
是高丽沦陷的十二逆贼
先拔出供奉主上殿下的铁枪
Pull out the spear of the one that served his majesty and dig underneath it.
然后从那个底部开始挖
快去把铁枪拔出来！
Go pull out the spear!
快点行动！
- Now! Move faster!
I said move it!
快点！
Go! Pull the spear out, now!
快拔出铁枪！
Pull out the spear, now!
勇敢的人会得到更大的回报
There will be a greater reward for those who show courage!
听到了吧？赶紧拔出来
You heard him! Pull out the spear!
快点！
Get a move on!
Hurry!
逃跑就死定了！
If you run, you're dead!
快点！
-机关？ -有机关 都退后
- A trap? - It's a trap! Get back!
退后！
崔莹
Choe Yeong.
（莹）
YEONG
这是对抗李成桂的高丽最后一名将帅
The last general of Goryeo who fought against Yi Seong-ye.
崔莹的将军旗
That's General Choe Yeong's flag.
崔莹
Choe Yeong.
被朝鲜开国功臣们围绕的
Goryeo's last general surrounded by the founders of Joseon.
高丽最后一名将帅
就是那个
That's the one.
大哥 有机关
Captain, the apparatus! The apparatus!
有机关！
可以了！
It worked!
果然是那个
Of course, that's the one.
你是什么？
What are you?
是鸟 还是鱼？
A bird or a fish?
What?
黄金
Gold! Unbelievable!
真有黄金
There really is gold here.
小幕这个混蛋 被我抓到就撕烂你
Mak-yi, you ass! I can't believe you.
If I find you,
I'll tear off your head!
找到了！
I found it!
我找到黄金了！
I found the gold!
在这里
He found it? Where?
是这里啊 小子们！
Over here, you jerks!
-找到了！ -黄金在哪里 幕团长？
- I found it! - Where's the gold, Captain Mak-yi?
-那边 -哪里？
- There. - Where is it?
你不是找到了吗？
You found it?
在哪里？
我问你在哪里！
Where is it?
这个混蛋
That little鈥?
你敢不敢再出来！
You better get back here!
你在叫什么？
Enough. Who are you talking to?
小团长
First mate鈥?
那个东西吧
鈥t was like
是长得像人类的鸟
a bird that looks like a man.
还是长得像鱼一样的人 反正
Or a man that looks like a bird-fish thing.
有一个奇怪的家伙咬着这么大的黄金
This creature had a huge piece of gold in it's mouth.
明明在这里 这样挥舞来着
He was right here, like this.
妈的
I call bullshit!
我受够了
The last straw.
-杀了他 -再也忍不下去了
- Kill him! - I'm tired of this!
砍掉你这该死的嘴！
That lying mouth!
-看那个 -那是什么？
- What is that? - What is that?
黄金
- Gold.
看到了吗？
Did you see?
相信吗？
Do you believe me?
相信吗！
相信！
那快去找吧
Then hurry up and find it.
黄金在等着我们
The gold is waiting here for us!
到嘴边了都吃不了的话
If you can't take it from here, you're not worthy to be a pirate!
就没有资格当海盗！
甚至不配当水母！
Let alone a jellyfish!
Yeah!
-开始找！ -开始找！
- Find it! - Find it!
你从哪儿找来的？
Where did you get it?
快说啊
Say something already!
你是在问鸟吗？
Are you asking the bird?
鸟？
Bird?
还不明白吗？
You still don't get it?
给我用一下 你们看啊
Here. Give me that. Watch this.
看到了吧？世界上
You saw that, right? You saw that?
哪有贪图黄金的野兽？
When have we ever seen an animal that wants gold?
见过吗？
Have you? Have you?
我是没见过 不知道别人怎么样
- No. - I haven't neither.
but you can't fool a former merchant.
但你骗不了前商人的眼睛的
You might fool the others,
所以你的意思是
Are you saying that is actually a person?
它是人吗？
郁闷死了 真是的
Ugh. This is so damn frustrating!
来 好言相劝的时候赶紧说
Come on. Say something while we're still being nice.
你从哪弄来的黄金？
Where did you get that gold, huh?
你看我一副好人脸吗？
I'm being nice.
非要看到血才能听到吗？
Do you have to bleed to start flapping that beak?
生平第一次见这么傻的人
I've never seen someone as stupid as you are.
对不起啊 鸟哥
Forgive him, birdie.
我 幕团长
I, Captain Mak-yi,
替我的手下向你道歉
apologize for this rotten bastard crewmember.
话说 你的首领在哪儿？
Could you tell us where your leader is?
什么？
- What is that?
大炮？
It's a cannon.
团长 那边有官船
Captain, the government ship.
开炮！
The ship's here.
Fire!
找到了！
Huh?
We found it! We found it!
快拉上来！
- Pull it up. Hurry!
真有啊
It actually exists.
拉上来！
Pull it up! Yeah!
什么动静？
这个鼠崽子
The little rat.
禹武治
Wu Mu-chi.
辛苦你了啊
You've done a good job finding a treasure that belongs to someone else.
寻找有主人的宝物
谁是主人？
And who is that?
我
Me.
我们砍下那个疯子的头吧
Leave it to us to cut off that crazy bastard's head!
拉上来！
不要停 开炮！
Don't stop now! Fire!
团长
What do we do?
怎么办？
Captain?
听着
Listen up.
不管今天是否与我战斗而死
Whether you die fighting with me today,
还是回首今天在后悔中度过
or turn your back and live in regret for abandoning us,
你们可以自己决定在哪里死
the choice of where you die is yours to make.
但作为团长 我可以保证
But I promise you as a captain,
我决不会死在这个岛上
I have no intention of dying on this island.
也不会让你们任何人
And I won't let any of you die
死在这个岛上
on this god-forsaken island either.
我要和团长一起去！
Captain, I will stay with you!
-我也是 -我也是
Me too! Me too!
团长
Captain, we must stay together from now on.
我们必须永远在一起
You live life only once.
人只活一次
大手大脚地花钱后再死吧
Let's have our way with gold and welcome our fate!
没错！
Yeah!
-抢夺官船！ -找到宝物！
Let's take down the government ship!
And find the treasure too!
好 从现在开始抢夺官船
Okay! Let's take the government ship now!
副团长去救头目
Quartermaster, go rescue your boss.
直到掠夺官船之前引诱敌军
Draw the enemy's attention until we take the ship.
过去的义贼们擅长爬山
As former bandits, we're good on land.
久违地和头目一起畅快玩一把吧
Let's climb that mountain, find our boss, and have a long overdue reunion!
玩一把！
- Let's go have some fun! - Let's go!
我们走！
Let's go! Let's go!
-我们走！ -我们走！
- Let's go! - Let's go!
让开 别挡路
Out of the way, man. You're blocking us.
Let's go!
走！
Forward!
我才是团长
I thought I was captain.
我们也去吧
Let's go too.
寻找黄金
To find the damn gold!
海琴！
Hae-geum!
（入）
这是什么？
- Where's the treasure? - All that's here are rocks!
-宝物在哪里？ -全都是石头
去找找！
- Find it! - Captain!
-让开 -抓住他！
Catch him!
让开！
抓住他！
Get him!
入？还要进哪儿啊？
"Entrance"? There's another entrance?
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
Huh?
你在那儿做什么？ 直接过来吧 赶紧的！
What are you doing? Let's get going!
Just come here!
直接过来啊
Let's go!
太没有默契了
Our teamwork is terrible, seriously!
夫兴秀！
Bu Heung-su!
你需要这个鬼怪面具吗？
Do you need this goblin mask?
这好像是寻宝物的最后一把钥匙
Seems like it's the final key to find the treasure.
如果你乖乖交出 我就放了你一命
If you hand it over now, I'll spare your life.
反正你也没有船载宝物
You probably don't even have a ship to carry the treasure, anyway.
船？
Ship?
一艘船就够了
But I only need one ship.
如果你不是懦夫 不如赌上宝物
If you're not a coward,
me against you.
来一场首领对决吧？
Let's duel for the treasure.
你别逃跑就行
Just don't run away.
-咦？ -咦？
- Huh? - Oh.
别动 这是首领对决！
Stop! This is a leader's duel.
咱快点吧
Can we go a little faster, please?
龙
Dragons.
龙要升天了
The dragons are awakening!
你还耍小聪明！
- You've been tricking me all along!
臭小子
You bastard!
要是被我抓到了
You'd better run, you turd!
我就撕断你的腿！
I'll rip your legs off if I catch you!
小子…
Got you!
Get him!
专心打架！
Why have you been trying to pick that up? Just focus on fighting!
什么东西？
What?
What's this?
一模一样
Huh? It's the same.
忍一忍 把脚抬起来！
我没有脸见您 团长
I have no excuses, Captain.
我们活下来了
We're alive? We're alive?
没事了
海琴呢？
And Hae-geum?
怎么回事？
是海盗！
There's pirates!
-这些混蛋 -都死定了！
- Prepare to die! - You're all dead, dammit!
-扶我一把 -赶紧减肥吧 你这个大胖子
Lose some weight.
我找到宝物了！
I found the treasure!
找到宝物了！
Whoo!
I found the treasure!
I found the鈥?
不是 怎么说呢
Wait. So鈥?
该死
Ah, shit.
鸟哥们
Birdies,
听我说
just listen to me.
我不是要私吞这些东西
I'm not saying I'm going to keep this all for myself.
首先要离开这个岛
I'm saying, first, let's get off this island, huh?
然后再公平分配嘛
Then we divide it evenly.
你们得知道 我的手下多得惊人
You should know I have an enormous number of subordinates, okay?
要是在这里磨磨蹭蹭被发现 那就是劳而无功…
If I get caught here dillydallying鈥?It's鈥?it's a waste of my-- Ow!
这臭小子
How dare you!
老虎不发威 当我是病猫啊
You're pushing your luck!
我可是海盗王…
I'm the Pirate King--
Huh?
团长 船现在很危险
Captain, the ship, it's in terrible condition!
必须立即停止战斗 先修船！
We have to stop fighting and repair it immediately!
必须先修船
We must repair the ship.
要是失去这艘船 所有人都会死！
If this ship sinks, we'll all die!
反正你都要死了 还担心什么
You're about to die, anyway. So why do you care?
来了
I've returned.
海盗王小幕
I'm here to save you all!
来救你们了！
It is I, Mak-yi, the Pirate King!
把剑放下！
Throw away your sword!
抓紧了！
Hold on tight.
-抓紧了！ -怎么回事？
- Hold on tight. - What's happening?
这次是凤凰要飞起来了吗？
Is a phoenix taking off this time or something?
快下来！
Get down quickly!
你还好吗？
Hey. You okay?
为什么我看到两艘船？
Why do I see two ships?
你也是吗？
You too?
那个闪烁的东西是什么？
Yeah, but what's that sparkly thing?
是朱芳的船吗？
Did Joo Bang's ship survive?
那都是黄金吗？
Is that all gold in that ship?
足够了
Well, look at that.
我可以建立新的王国了
That's enough to build a new kingdom.
是黄金！
Gold!
把他们都杀了
Kill them all.
都杀掉
Kill them all!
快点过去！
Everybody, cross over!
团长！
Captain!
-开炮！ -快点啊 团长！
- Shoot at them! - Hurry, Captain!
发射！
Fire!
-团长！ -团长！
Captain! Let's go!
-不要啊！ -团长！
- Captain! - No!
Captain!
I got you!
你这个混蛋！
团长
Captain!
别碰那里 那里很痛
Hey, hey. Don't touch there. It hurts!
差点就死了
God. I almost died.
团长没事！
The captain's okay!
Yeah!
团长是我！
I'm still the captain!
他又开始了
It's starting again.
在海洞中与无数巨龙搏斗后
After a battle against countless dragons in a sea cave,
我带来了这些宝物
I brought these treasures.
那里有多少条龙？
How many dragons were there?
3872条
已经找到宝物了 我们回家吧！
Now that we have the treasure,
it's time to go home!
回家吧！
Let's go home!
那是什么？
-地震？ -怎么回事？
What's that sound?
什么动静？
What was that?
一群龙要升天了
A horde of dragons has awakened.
扬帆起航！
Raise the sails!
团长！
Captain!
我发出信号时 你们把帆桁固定住！
When I give the signal, be sure to secure the sails!
是
Yes, Captain!
各就各位！
Everyone, get ready!
打起精神来 小子！
Pull yourself together, men!
就是现在！
Now pull!
拉！
Pull!
帮我！
Someone help me!
使劲拉！
我们活下来了吗？
Are we alive?
应该是阴间吧
This must be the afterlife.
活下来了！
We're alive! We're alive!
We're alive!
活下来了！
你做到了 团长！
So you made it, Captain!
现在轮到我了吗？
'Cause it's my turn now!
不要死
Don't die on me,
禹武治
Wu Mu-chi.
死在这里
If I die on this mountain,
浪儿会记得我吗？
will Rang remember me?
I wonder.
-头目！ -头目！
胜利永远属于强者
In the end, the strongest always wins.
禹武治！
Wu Mu-chi!
是这边！
-头目！ -姜燮！
- Boss! - Kang-seop!
禹武治也做到了
Wu Mu-chi succeeded as well.
干得好！
Look at this!
我找到宝物了！
I found the treasure!
Huh?
海琴
Hae-geum.
还活着吗？
Is she alive?
你吃饭了吗？
Hey. Did you eat yet?
朱芳怎么样了呢？
I wonder what happened to Joo Bang.
没有船 应该没有办法离开岛
He wouldn't have been able to leave the island without a boat.
沉睡在岛上的某个地方吧
He's probably asleep on the island somewhere,
怀着亡国之恨
full of sorrow for his ruined country.
什么亡国啊
What ruined country?
高丽已经重建了
Goryeo's been rebuilt.
以朝鲜之名
Joseon's it's name, now.
百姓就是国家 就是千年王国的栋梁
A country is its people,
the pillars聽of a thousand-year dynasty.
现在找到了宝物
So now that we found the treasure, um鈥?
-头目打算怎么做？ -头目？
鈥hat's Boss going to do?
Boss?
如果你非要留在船上 那我可以考虑合作
Well, if you insist on staying on the ship,
I'll have to rethink the leadership then.
-打算怎样做？ -我想想
- What do you say? - I need to think it over.
你要想到什么时候？
How long are you going to think about it?
假期结束了
Your vacation is over鈥?
团长
Captain.
全体注意
Attention!
你真要离开吗？
Are you really leaving us?
我也没办法
Do I have any other choice?
一船容不下两条龙
You cannot have two dragons on one ship.
如果有缘 总有一天会再相见
If it is our fate, I suppose we will meet again.
只要你不离开大海
As long as you're still on the sea, Captain.
不过团长 这里哪有岛啊？
But I'm confused. Where's the island here?
我明明要求把我送到安全的岛上
I asked to be taken to a safe island.
岛就在那边
The island is over there.
在哪里？
Where?
那个岛啊
That island.
那是岛吗？是礁石
That's not an island, it's a rock.
我们把重点放在了你所说的安全性
We paid particular attention to the safety you mentioned.
既没有山中野兽 也没有平原野兽
There are no mountain beasts or wild animals.
而且连官军也没有
What's more, no soldiers either.
Exactly!
我敢断言没有比那里更安全的地方
I assure you there's no safer place.
是啊
He's right!
没有水喝 也没有地方伸腿啊
When there's no fresh water, or room to stretch your legs!
世界上没有完美的地方
There is no place in this world that is perfect.
没错
Exactly!
放下仇恨吧
Joo Bang, rest in peace.
我会像义贼一样
'Cause we are honest bandits. we'll use it well to help the common folk.
帮助老百姓
你还没回答我呢
So you didn't answer my question.
Hmm?
Ah.
Oh, Hae-rang.
真是的 等我一会儿嘛
- Hmm? - Hey. Just stay still, will you?
干什么？
What?
回答
My answer.
打算留下来吗？
Are you saying you'll stay?
曾是高丽第一剑客的我
The former Greatest Swordsman
愿与你同行到天涯海角
chooses to walk alongside you.
傻子
Idiot.
那样的话 至少也得有点表示
For me to know, you have to do this.
团长！
Captain?
Huh? What?
他们什么时候好上的？
Since when were those two鈥?
没发现吗？剁鱼头的时候啊
You didn't know? While they were cutting fish heads.
你们又搞哪出？
What's going on?
这些人
Them too?
宝物有什么用！
What's the use of treasure, dammit?
我不需要这些
Ugh. I don't need any of this.
请停下来！
Please, stop already! Stop!
拜托！
Come on!
字幕翻译：林樟榕